

Varvara Lazarenko

Address Nijmegen, The Netherlands Telephone

+31 6 2662 9839

E-mail varlazoa@gmail.com Date of birth 29.12.1998 (26 years) LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly motivated and hardworking graduate with a Master's degree in Medical biology. Having worked in fundamental research setting as well as in clinical trials development, I am passionate about translational research and societal aspects of healthcare innovations. With a strong biomedical foundation and a keen interest in disseminating knowledge, I envision a career in academia or consultancy.

EDUCATION

09/2022 - 08/2024

MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA 7.63/10.00
- ✓ Principal subjects: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Methods in Societal Research, Reaching the Sustainable **Development Goals**
- ✓ Projects: «HTA of a Medical Guidance App for International Students in the NL»
 - «A Shared Ownership Model of the Green Corridor, Nijmegen»
 - «A Circular Alternative to Single-Use Cups Within the Dutch Train System»
- ✓ Master thesis: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care»

09/2016 - 06/2020

BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Specialisation: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA 4.83/5.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Microbiology, Genetics, Biochemistry, Biophysics, Immunology, Embryology
- √ <u>Skills</u>: PCR, gel electrophoresis, wire myography, western blotting, ELISA, immunohistochemistry, intracellular recording (microelectrodes, patch clump), behaviour testing (open field test, elevated plus maze, light-dark box test)
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats»

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2024 - 08/2024

Intern at Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care

HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- √ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

02/2023 - 08/2023

Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory

Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ In vivo Ca²⁺ imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (mice, handling & feeding, craniotomy)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

Assistant at the Science department of the Contract Research Organization 08/2021 - 08/2022 **LABMGMU**, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing designs, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for >35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- ✓ >30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

10/2020 - 10/2021

Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological (wire myography technique, rat coronary and renal arteries) and molecular (RNA extraction, reverse transcription, qPCR) experiments
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats: housing, care, breeding)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at the <u>virtual conference ARTERY20</u>, 23-24 October 2020, and at the 28th International Scientific Conference "Lomonosov-2021", 12-23 April 2021

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism, Rotor-Gene Q Series, and MS Office softwares

LANGUAGES

Russian (native), English (fluent – C_2), German (intermediate – B_1 - B_2), Dutch (low intermediate – A_2 - B_1), French (beginner - A_1)

ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

- 2022-2024 Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University 2020-2021
- Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements
 - 2021 Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

CERTIFICATES

- 2023 A course on ex. Art. 9 of the Dutch Act on animal experimentation, Radboudumc
- 2021 An upgrade training on ICH GCP guidelines, LABMGMU

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY

- Mentorship of the international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro 2024
- Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen 2023
- 2022-2023 Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
- Mentorship of the first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow 2018-2021

HOBBIES

Volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., Lazarenko Varvara S., Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. Frontiers in physiology, 13: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- 2. Lazarenko Varvara, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. Artery Research, 26(S1): S58. https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., Lazarenko V.S., Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina, 54(2): 89-95. https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639